This is it!
I concede.
Matthew-san, you really are good at this.
I bet you beat Ikta-san or
Yatori-san if you played them.
No way.
Huh? Is that kind of a sore spot for you?
It's not just chess.
It's everything.
Don't you feel the same way, Haru?
About how they're...
On a whole different level?
Sorry!
I always say everything I'm thinking.
I know.
Anyway...
Are you mad?
No.
I'm going to the War Records room.
I want to know more about
the river-defense formation.
I'm impressed.
Good luck!
A whole different level, huh?
I know that, but I can't give up!
Someday I'll show them what
Matthew Tetdrich is really capable of!
I was able to hit them,
from that distance!
Being distant from the target
isn't always a bad thing.
For one, it makes it harder
for them to hit you,
and harder for them to find you at all.
And more than anything,
you don't have to worry when you fire.
My flaw, my worries,
and what I want to do...
You've known for a long time,
haven't you, Ikkun?
At the Base of the Stairs of God
Ikta-san,
should you really be sleeping here?
Don't worry.
Wherever I sleep,
I'll always save the right side
of the bed for you.
Anyway, what were you reading?
Oh, yeah.
Anarai's box is about to open.
Whose box?
It's a safe, basically,
with intellectual property inside.
Did I tell you I studied under Anarai Kahn?
The man who sought asylum in Kioka, yes?
Science, was it?
You said you learned from him.
Yes. I'm one of his students.
The results of the research
we all worked on together
were first put into Anarai's box,
and no one except us was
allowed to learn them.
But, in exchange for
recognizing his asylum claim,
Kioka wanted technology
with military applications.
And so, to keep things balanced with Kioka,
he told us what he was giving them.
Um, what does that mean?
Eh, guess I must be boring you.
Well, it just means that the
battlefield's about to evolve again.
What a waste of good knowledge.
It's finally time to go
the Northern Region, huh?
We're heading to the garrison in Somin.
It's at the base of a mountain range
in the sticks.
Those Sinack hicks are everywhere,
so it's not safe.
Did I hear someone making fun
of the Northern Region?
It's just simple prejudice to think there's
nothing worth seeing in the sticks.
You, especially, Matthew.
You don't understand
the wonders of the Sinacks.
Huh? You know a lot about the Sinacks?
I visited a Sinack village with old man
Anarai as part of a research expedition.
We investigated the weather and
geological strata in the high mountains,
but my personal favorite part
was getting to know the locals.
They're mountain barbarians, right?
What was fun about that?
If I had to give you one reason,
the girls are beautiful and energetic.
I thought you liked older women.
Your standards are different
than mine, so that's useless.
I'm not just talking about their appearance.
It's an extremely matriarchal society,
and that's created its own unique traditions.
For example...
The girls visit your bed at night?!
That's so lewd!
The world's a big place, Matthew.
You guys are in a good mood.
What are you talking about?
It's probably best not to ask.
Nine out of ten times,
it's something indecent.
I wasn't talking about anything—
By indecent, do you mean something like
the way Haro's sweaty
shirt sticks to her chest,
so you can see every inch of her curves?
Something wonderful like that?
Apologize.
Only a truly disgusting man would
say something like that to a woman.
So?
We were discussing the trip north.
A six-month deployment, wasn't it?
Outside of dealing with thieves and
monitoring the mountain people,
it's a very dull post, I hear.
Yatori, aren't you going to be bored?
No, it's perfect.
I want as many real battles
under my belt as possible.
I wish a certain person
were that enthusiastic.
Kanna!
They're here! They're here!
The brand spanking-new officer candidates!
The ones who saved
the princess are here, too!
Great Alafatra Survey Records
Imperial Army Northern Region Garrison
I welcome both the high-Level
Officer candidates,
and their training units,
once more this year.
We at the Northern Garrison
are very glad you're here.
Northern Garrison Commander
Lt. General Tamtooktsk Safida
I'm reluctant to discuss
unpleasant matters so soon,
but you're well aware of
the fall of the Eastern Region.
If only I and a few of my men had been there
when the Kioka barbarians dared
trespass on Imperial land...
Our eventual counterattack on Kioka
depends on the loyalty and
patriotism of us soldiers.
As the future leaders of our military,
I pray your patriotism is firm and pure.
Sorry for the short speech,
but that's all I have.
How was that short?
Eternal prosperity to the land
the Emperor rules, and we soldiers protect!
Cheers!
Continue your chats as you listen to me.
I am the garrison commander's aide,
Major Yuskshiram Toakk.
I'll explain what you'll be doing here.
Is he okay?
You can find the organizational hierarchy
posted in the barracks hallway,
I could see him dropping dead at any minute.
He's probably got a lot on his mind.
The chain of the command is posted
there, too, so make sure you look at it.
Since he's working for
a boss who doesn't have one.
That's all.
If you have any questions, ask them now.
It's so obvious who's doing what here.
Hey.
Having fun?
Yes.
Thanks.
You have a light spirit, too, don't you?
Warrant Officer Ikta Solork,
Light Troops Platoon 3.
This is Kus, my partner.
Northern Garrison 1st Regiment
9th Illumination Company Commander
First Lieutenant Senpa Sazaluf.
I'll be your instructor for a while.
This is light spirit Key, my partner.
Nice to meet you.
I hear there's a problem child mixed in
with the knights everyone's talking about.
Would that be you?
When I'm with them I don't fit in,
so I'm keeping my distance.
You sure don't look like a knight.
That handsome boy over there might, but...
You're harsh!
I hate him!
I hate all hot guys, who get
women coming to them
even without saying a word!
Oh, jeez...
I've been waiting for this,
daughter of Igsem!
Do you need something from me?
Northern Garrison 1st Regiment
22nd Breastplate Cavalry
Platoon Commander
Listen well!
My name is Deinkun Hargunska!
I am 26 years old!
My rank is Warrant Officer!
I'm well aware of your name!
Now, let our blades do the talking.
Lieutenant General Safida, I have
received a request for a duel.
Is there someplace we can use?
What do we do?
Here is probably fine.
Very well. Do it here.
However, Warrant Officer Hargunska's
skills with a blade
are the finest in the Northern Garrison.
Hey, what are you doing?
The two-blade style of the Igsem clan
is for fighting multiple foes at once.
If I have one opponent,
I only need one blade.
You must not think much of my skills, then.
What a vulgar display.
Yatori's swordsmanship is not
meant to be gawked at.
That's incorrect.
Hey, you can't—
The Igsem style is meant to be gawked at.
This is a traditional farce put on whenever
an Igsem arrives at another garrison.
What?
The two-weapon style is a special privilege
given to the Igsem
at the behest of the Emperor,
as a symbol of their invincibility.
As long as they do not lose a swordfight,
the military allows it.
So, this is all just a show
for them to gawk at.
The Igsems value order in
the Empire very highly.
To continue carrying
two swords on their belt,
they must show everyone their superiority,
so as to protect that order.
Is Yatori-san being pushed back?
No, she hasn't hit back yet, but...
Yes.
Her position hasn't changed
since the start of the battle.
The Igsems are the embodiment of
the legend of invincibility.
Your strikes were as strong as steel.
I am honored to have had
the opportunity to fight you.
Splendid, Yatorishino Igsem!
I suppose that's Yatori for you.
It's all to protect the order of the Empire.
She risks her life to protect you
because she believes,
without doubt, that you
will fulfill your duties
as a member of the imperial family
for the rest of your life.
Don't forget that, Princess.
No matter how great your dreams may be,
don't forget that.
Well, to be honest, you guys
came here at a great time.
Things were pretty tense until a bit ago,
since it was so bad at the Eastern Garrison.
We thought they might ask for reinforcements.
You didn't want to go?
Who would?
But, if there was a sizable
enough group of reinforcements,
the course of the battle might have changed.
In the North, we call courageous people
like you "central-type soldiers".
The people who are motivated even
after coming up here to the north.
People like that are a minority around here.
It's all because of the Alafatra mountains.
Why?
That's right...
Great Alafatra is the stairway to God.
No enemy has ever crossed over these
mountains in the history of the Empire.
Yes, that's right, Warrant Officer Remeon.
Even without external threats,
I think there are internal ones
who live there.
Yeah.
Our job is just that.
Keeping the Sinack mountain peoples
in check, correct?
That's right.
They're Imperials, but not Katjvarnans.
We've had several small-scale
conflicts with them.
But about two years ago
they stopped causing trouble.
The last six months we haven't even
sent out any punitive raids.
First Lieutenant, what is the
point of this exercise?
We've been going over the same
area for three hours.
This isn't training us for anything.
That's right.
This is a threat that
we're calling an exercise.
We show them our forces and use
silent pressure to keep the peace.
Warrant Officer Solork,
you have nothing to say?
Reporting, First Lieutenant.
I have a message from Warrant Officer Solork.
"I have broken military regulations and
voluntarily entered the detention barracks.
The regulation I broke was regarding
leaving the squad during exercises..."
I refuse to accept this!
Why are all the books in our
barracks being confiscated?
Private First Class Kanna, is that how
you address a superior officer?
Daring to lecture me with no rank?
If you've got time to read books,
go run and build up stamina!
Wait!
If you're reacting like that,
this must be yours.
Great Alafatra Survey Records.
Th-This was authored by
Anarai the Blasphemer!
Th-The contents of the book have
nothing to do with the author!
I've had it with you!
Grit your teeth.
Oh, no.
That's not how you use that book.
Who the hell are you?!
A passing Imperial Knight.
My task in life is to banish all the tears
from all the girls in the world.
Imperial Knight?
One of the knights everyone's talking about?
I apologize for the rudeness.
But there's something very interesting here.
The invention of the printing press
has made books far easier to attain,
and some books have become huge hits.
They're still not exactly cheap
for the average person, though.
Even used, this amount of books
is worth a fortune.
That's what you thought,
wasn't it, First Lieutenant?
What are you saying, you bastard?!
So, you took them to sell for yourself?
D-Don't be stupid!
The Rose of Miyakanne,
The Life of Dalis.
Good choices.
You already know who
you'll sell them to, right?
You bastard!
Enough with your yammering!
I was going to let you off easy because
you're a favorite of the Third Princess.
A question for you, First Lieutenant.
Do you like insects?
I don't care about them! Bugs are bugs!
But there are some of them
who are highly toxic.
It's dangerous to try and handle them
without any knowledge.
Like everything else, a soldier's heart is
strong enough to overcome those difficulties!
One last thing.
If you think the soldier spirit
grants you omnipotent powers,
you're going to get hurt.
Don't talk like you know anything!
Here you go!
Congrats on a successful mission, Sergeantula!
They stay out of direct sunlight
during the day,
so you can find them under eaves and roofs.
If he'd read this book,
he would've known that.
This is yours, right?
Th-Thank you, Warrant Officer.
Think you could call me Ikkun?
What's your name?
Northern Garrison 1st Regiment,
Private First Class Kanna Temari.
My partner is Tab the wind spirit.
Nice to meet you.
Um... Ikkun-dono.
Ikkun-dono, huh?
Well, I guess it works.
Hey, Kanna?
What was your favorite part of that book?
Um... the analysis of
the Aldera religion, I think.
The Aldera religion?
Not the part on the spirit worship
of the Sinacks?
C-Correct.
It says that when you analyze
the Aldera religion of the Empire
in light of the Sinack's spirit worship,
you see many things that seem strange.
I've never seen a guy ditch exercises
to go pick up girls before.
Kanna! We'll see each other again!
We're both students of science!
If you're reading that book,
you're a student of Anarai like me!
You and I are fellow students!
I see you're having a good time.
But, you know, I hope you're
still alive to see her again!
Fellow students?
Welcome to the world of science
Try to endure this for three days.
No food, no water.
That'll kill me!
Until you can stop talking
all the damn time, then.
Listen, what were you thinking
when you got to where you are now?
It was 100% bad luck.
Sheesh...
I heard you were weird, but...
Hey! Hey, don't go that way!
Hey!
First Lieutenant,
what is this?
Nanaku Daru.
When do we begin?
Our war to recover the stolen Hahashiku.
We won't wait for the next
Grateful Spirit Festival.
Can we win against those
terrible demons of the plains?
You know, Meraize,
our world right now is only half.
So we're going to get back
the other half of the world that was stolen.
Great Alafatra, the stairway to God,
had protected the Empire from
external threats for years.
Imperial Year 906, July.
Dark clouds were gathering from within...
Next time: The Northern Katjvarna Rebellion.
The Northern Katjvarna Rebellion